hey everyone thanks for listening to the Grow
Your Life podcast my name is Jeremiah Kowski
on this podcast I help mentors trainers and
coaches scale their businesses and make crazy
amounts of money online using direct response
marketing and the tactics that I've used for
over 22 years in the industry to tell you exactly
what's working right now today to get more money
now I want to talk about something that I notice
is a bit of an issue when it comes to coaches and
mentors is we care a lot about people that's not
the problem that's a good thing that's what drives
us to do what we do and why we mentor people the
reason why we do what we do is because we want
to help others and it's a great way to make
money and you know that but you don't want to
make money the priority so here's what I want to
tell you is that I find often times that coaches
and mentors are way too concerned with how their
prospects feel i'm not talking about their clients
see when it comes to my paid clients I really
do care about them getting results it's not
just lip service me saying that it's something
that I really I put all of my effort and energy
outside of my family and my relationship with
God into getting my clients results and if you're
a client of mine you know that when it comes
to my prospects however let's say you're not
a paid client of mine and you're watching this
listening I mean this with all due respect but
I could not care less about your opinions or
feelings whether you're tired of me emailing
you too often or what I post on social media or
how I say something and and sure okay devil's
advocate kind of thing here to persuade people
to buy you they need to like you but here's what
I do i'm just going to assume everybody likes
me just how I am i'm not going to censor myself
change it and I'm not going to adjust my behavior
in order to make somebody want to buy something
i've been in this industry long enough that I know
exactly what the behaviors are that get a result
so if you follow those specific behaviors one of
which could be emailing your email list at least
once every other day three to four times a week
and you might say "Well gosh Jeremiah I'm on so
many lists i don't want to spam people i don't
want to annoy them with my emails." Can I tell
you this that thinking right there is one of
the root causes why you might not be getting
the kind of results that you want to because
I've noticed a lot of mentors and and and and
quite frankly again if this offends you that I say
that we can have a conversation and I understand
but like like realize that that that energy of
okay the the opportunity to grow your business
by sending email out to your email list is so
great it is the most effective consistent way
to bring in cash flow for your business is by
building an email list and then emailing those
people consistently and then you have offers and
it becomes a loop it's like this okay we get the
email right here we got the email then we're going
to send them offers if they don't grab the offer
we're going to email them again and we're going to
send them offers and it's a loop that just keeps
on looping until they end up buying becoming
a customer or unsubscribing unsubscribing
and so I'm equally unconcerned if people
unsubscribe they dislike my emails or something
like that or maybe I'm posting too much and so
I had a guy once contact me he's like "You post
way too often on social media Jeremiah i'm going
to unfriend you." Great go ahead please so like
in that if if we cannot put so much mental energy
around tiptoeing around the feelings and opinions
of our prospect i used to do these live events
and I still do them from time to time it's not
as often and they're a different format i have one
coming up here soon but where I would do live Q&A
with people I'd never met on the internet before
they would come up on camera and I'll tell you
some people were very angry at the things that I
was saying because it I believe it challenged some
belief about what was ethical in them like this
idea i mean the somebody got angry with me that
I charge $2,000 for my coaching program which is
actually really cheap compared to what a lot of
people charge angry and it used to concern me
it used to bother me it used to eat me alive
because I wanted the acceptance and the approval
i thought that maybe that would turn into sales
realized that you know what a prospect I ended
up literally having to block this person from
my cuz people had to pay money to be able to join
the Q&A they had paid like 27 bucks or something
i blocked their credit card from being able to
purchase on my website because every time they
were on it was negative and so I did not concern
and then I got the nastiest email about the fact
that they couldn't register so like hear me
out here my mental health my sanity my income
is directly correlated to the fact that I am okay
with disappointing a prospect upsetting them them
not wanting to listen to me okay now let's go to
the flip side on the positive side with my clients
I still encourage people not to get codependent
with their clients but you should concern yourself
with how can I get them results how can I do the
very best of my ability to get my clients results
that's what a great coach does and there's nuance
to that of course like at some point there are
certain people who literally are just not going
to do the work and you've done everything in your
power to help them and above and beyond and they
still won't do the work and then they will might
even blame you for why they didn't do the work
i've had this happen this is what happens in the
coaching world you got to shake your shoe off
dust your shoulders off and realize this is not
my responsibility i did the very best I could
to the best of my ability and that's all that
matters do the best that you can to the best of
your ability and our abilities and capabilities
are very different for everybody for instance like
my capability some coaches they could literally be
one-on-one all day long with their clients i got
two kids and I and I have a couple of different
businesses that I build i don't have the capacity
to be on live 247 with my clients but I give the
opportunity for them to message me 24/7 and I
respond back and I'm available to provide that
value see the difference so whatever you're
capable of to the maximum of your capability
and we don't feel any guilt or shame about if
our capability might be different than somebody
else like my capability when I was single was way
different i spent a lot of that time playing more
video games i play a lot less video games now
though I still do i like it the new uh Madden
football game is coming out in about a month and
a half and I'm kind of stoked for that okay so
anyways I love the football game so anyways all
that to say do not let the opinions the feelings
the judgments of potential business stop you from
just being yourself having fun loving what you're
doing showing up in a powerful way and I had to
I had to tell myself this i had to learn this
myself because I found myself constantly trying
to censor myself and make myself more palatable
more approachable to certain people because I
thought that would produce better results now
yes I'm growing in my skill my body language how
I show up there's certain cadence and things and
tone and stuff like that that you can do that
helps people connect with you better when I use
my hands and I inflect my voice up and down like
this that there is some nuance to that and I've
learned how to use that to be able to get my point
across better when to slow down when to speed up
and this is just as somebody who's been around
this industry long enough you learn these things
actually learn them probably a lot later than
most people most people learn those things at
the beginning of their career i learned them about
in the last year which is very interesting okay i
had like a tone that I thought had to be my tone
and now I'm like "Okay you know what it's going to
be me people are going to connect with me they're
going to like that that's the type of content I
like to connect with." And so take it or leave it
you don't like it i love you but me okay all right
so all that to say I just want to encourage
you like have fun with your business really
and don't put so much energy and time and effort
into what people are going to perceive about you
be consistent show up consistently
make content and have offers the
rest will work itself out trust me
whenever my business has struggled
I wasn't consistent and I was way
too worried about pleasing others
and when it thrived I let go of the of the brakes
i released the brakes let them go and just went
down the roller coaster imagine you're at the top
of a roller coaster and you're just letting go of
a brake line that's kind of what you got to do in
your business a little bit of reckless abandon but
you're strapped in you got guard rails right stay
within the guardrails stay in your lane i think
that's important i think I think this idea what I
love is this concept it's like like a little bit
of reckless abandon combined with guard rails and
staying in your lane like that's the key that's
the right that's the right angle for marketing
that's right where it's at right there where you
have fun you flow but you're within the boundaries
you got boundaries we got the We got that going on
all right listen I know this has helped somebody
if this if you want to help somebody else pass
on this podcast episode and if you want to
work with me personally I'd love to have you
join my Wealthy Coach Academy program where we're
helping coaches trainers and mentors know exactly
what steps to take to scale their businesses
to make incredible life-changing amounts of
money i'd love to be your mentor to help you do
that like I have for thousands over the years i
want to get you results all right we'll talk soon
grow your life everybody have a good one [Music]